RIE KIYONO AT NATIONALS
（清野利惠選手在全國大賽預賽中 驚豔眾人，橫掃全場）
I can't stand this!
我真是受不了！
Kiyono gets all the attention.
清野出盡了風頭
And you don't even have any good university offers.
卻沒一間大學錄取妳
It's all because of your injury!
全都是因為妳的傷！
There's no use bringing that up now.
現在提這個也沒用
Mr. Sakuragi, where did you get this?
櫻木老師，你是從哪找到這個的？
I got an anonymous e-mail.
我收到了一封匿名電郵
SELLING TATSUMI GAKUEN
（龍海學園出售計畫）
The land around the school
可是圍繞著學校的土地
has been nearly all bought up!
幾乎早已經被收購了
They're serious! What should we do, Chairman?
他們是認真的 我們該怎麼辦，理事長？
They've bought up so much.
他們已經收購了那麼多土地
Ours is the only plot left.
我們是唯一剩下的地區了
That horrible man!
那傢伙！
The former chairman's involved?
前任理事長和這有關聯嗎？
Chairman. I think it's about time to explain.
理事長，我想是時候向他們解釋了
My trickster father.
我那騙子父親
He's trying to sell this school.
他在試著出售這間學校
Sell the school? But why?
出售？這間學校嗎？為了什麼呢？
There's a plan to build a resort complex here.
有人計畫在這裡建度假村
The local residents are opposed.
本地的居民都反對
Of course, I have taken a hard opposition stance.
當然，我也持堅決反對的立場
But my father values money over the school and students.
但比起學校和學生 我父親更加重視金錢
He can get three times the usual price now.
他現在能獲得市價的三倍
Didn't he want to save the school from financial ruin
他不是想把學校從財務危機解救出來
and make it a high-level school?
並打造成一流學校嗎？
That's just a facade. His true aim
那只是幌子，他真正的目的
is to have me resign.
是要讓我辭職
He can't sell the land without the chairman's consent.
不經理事長的同意 他不能出售這片土地
So I was standing in his way.
所以說，我正擋著他的路
I thought something was up.
我就知道有內情
Saying "Quit if five students get into UTokyo."
說什麼“五位學生考進東大就辭職”
He even made a contract.
他甚至還準備了一份合約
So he did. If five students get in…
真的啊，那如果五位學生考上了…
It's over for me and for this school.
我就完了，這間學校也完了
No…
不是吧…
How could he play so dirty…
他怎麼可以耍那麼卑鄙的手段…
We mustn't allow such tyranny!
我們絕對不能接受這樣的暴政！
He said it was for the students
他一面說為學生著想
while selling the school for money!
一面為了錢把學校賣出去！
Vice Principal Takahara…
高原主任…
Overturning this contract would be…
但要推翻這合約…
Nearly impossible.
幾乎不可能
Hang on, wait.
等等
This means Mizuno Law Office is also in trouble.
這意思是水野律師事務所也有麻煩了
Sounds about right.
的確是這樣啊
My original contract said if we get five in, you'll contract me,
我原本的合約寫明 如果把五位學生送進東大
Mizuno Law Office, for the next five years, right?
你們就會和水野律師事務所 簽下未來五年的合約，對吧？
-Right? -Ah, yes.
-對吧？ -嗯，對
But if five students get in,
但要是五位學生考上
the chairman and the whole school will go.
理事長和整間學校就會完了
And if five don't get in, no contract.
而如果沒有五位考上，合約就沒了
No matter the outcome,
無論結果是什麼
your contract is over.
妳的合約都完了
It's not funny.
這根本不好笑
My dream of making bank.
我賺大錢的夢想
-My debt… -Hm?
-我的債務… -什麼？
Hang on.
等等
There's a simple solution.
有個簡單的解決方案
Just get four students in.
讓四位學生考上
The chairman and the school can remain.
那就能保住理事長和學校了
Takahara will get fired, but we can hire him back.
高原會被解雇 但我們可以再把他請回來
And Mizuno Law Office.
而水野律師事務所
We can make a new contract with you too.
我們可以再和妳簽一份新的合約
Everything works out.
這樣一切問題就解決了
Victory to everyone!
大家都是贏家！
You do talk sense sometimes.
你偶爾也會說些有用的話啊
No!
不可以！
If we limit it to four students,
要是我們只限制四位學生能考上
think of how the hardworking children would feel.
想想那些努力的孩子們是什麼感覺
We mustn't get the students involved in our adult problems.
大人的問題 絕對不能讓孩子們捲進來
That the thought even entered your mind,
腦袋出竟然冒出這樣的想法
you're a failure as an educator!
你作為教育者真是失敗！
I was mistaken.
我錯了
Disqualified!
不合格！
Surely there's another way.
一定有其它方法吧
Chairman! I'll help you.
理事長，我會助妳一臂之力
I'll support you in any way I can to help the school and students.
為了學校和學生，我會盡全力支持妳
Thanks.
謝謝
Leave the issue of the school sale to us.
學校出售的問題就留給我們處理吧
Mr. Sakuragi and Ms. Mizuno, focus on teaching the students.
櫻木老師和水野老師 你們教育專科的學生們
Of course we will.
當然了
Even so,
不過
who sent that e-mail to Mr. Sakuragi?
是誰寄電郵給櫻木老師的？
I'll look into it.
那個我會去查
I know a specialist.
我認識一位專家
Okay, thanks.
好，拜託了
Look what you've done.
妳看看妳都幹了什麼
We're stuck with this job that won't even pay.
我們現在被這沒酬勞的工作困住了
Take responsibility! Accepting it without due diligence!
給我負責任！沒調查過就接下這工作
Shush.
吵死了
How could I predict this?
我怎麼會料到有這種事？
You were gone for two years.
我才想哭呢，你消失了兩年
I built the Mizuno Law Office,
我成立了水野律師事務所
working desperately to get this far.
拼命努力才走到了這一步
To fail no matter the result,
最後，無論結果如何都會破產
it's not even funny.
這一點都不好笑
If we face failure either way,
要是我們無論如何都會失敗
we might as well get them in and build up our own reputation.
我們更該讓他們考上 建立我們的聲譽
Listen. We have seven students now,
聽著，我們現在有七位學生
but only Kosugi is at the passing line now.
但現在只有小杉在合格線上
Seto is working hard, but far from passing.
瀨戶很努力，但離通過實在太遠
Fujii plays tough, but psychologically he's the weakest.
還有藤井雖然很強 但心理層面卻是最弱的
And there's Iwasaki…
還有岩崎…
Iwasaki?
岩崎？
Summer's almost here.
夏天快到了
You've got to step up!
妳得加大力度！
I'm the one who could cry.
我才是那個有資格哭的人
I know. I understand.
我知道，我明白啦
-You're starting the morning strong. -Of course we are.
-你們一大早就很有鬥志啊 -當然了
I never want an E again.
我不想再考E了
I never want an ugly score like that again.
我再也不想考出這種爛成績了
Good attitude. But listen.
很好的態度，但是
Studying like mad is not the answer.
拼命學習並不是解決問題的方法
Huh? What do you mean?
啊？什麼意思？
The practice exam has shown where you stand.
模擬考已經顯示了你們現在的落點
You've got to make the most of that.
你們必須先充分利用這點
In other words…
換句話說…
Know your distance from UTokyo.
看清你和東大之間的距離
Distance from UTokyo?
和東大之間的距離？
Studying for entrance exams means closing that distance.
為入學考念書意味著減少那距離
How can you shorten that distance?
你要怎麼縮短那距離？
Calculate it from your current position.
從你現在的落點算起
Devise the fastest and most certain strategy.
制定一個最快、最可靠的策略
Your distance from UTokyo is your goal minus your current score.
你和東大的距離 是你的目標分數減去目前的分數
Think about how you can close the distance.
想想你可以怎麼縮短這距離
How? Isn't studying the only way?
怎麼縮短？念書不是唯一的途徑嗎？
You'll never succeed with such a rough strategy.
用這麼粗糙的策略，妳是不會成功的
Mizuno, the handouts.
水野，講義
What's this?
這是什麼？
Those are uniquely tailored strategies I made for each of you.
這是我為你們每人量身打造的策略
Uniquely tailored?
量身打造？
Hang on, I'm applying for Natural Sciences 1.
等等，我要申請的是理科一類
Are you serious about UTokyo?
你對東大是認真的嗎？
Then let go of that idea.
是的話就放棄那想法吧
-Huh? -It's not just you.
-什麼？ -不只是你
Science applicants, Amano, Iwasaki, and Kenta.
申請理科的天野、岩崎、健太
You're all applying to Natural Sciences 2.
你們都申請理科二類
I don't understand. Why are you putting me with them?
莫名其妙 為什麼把我和他們放在同一組？
Listen. Natural Sciences 1 is easier so it gets more applicants.
聽著，理科一類更容易 所以也會有更多考生
That drives up the minimum passing score.
這也就拉高了最低合格分數
So it's harder to get in.
所以反而更難通過
Natural Sciences 3 is out of the question.
理科三類我們就不考慮了
The only ones getting in are aliens.
只有外星人才考得進
Natural Sciences 2 has had a relatively low minimum score lately.
理科二類近年的最低合格分數相對低
Depending on the year, it's possible to get in with less than 50%.
具體要看年份 但有可能以低於滿分的50%進入
-It's a shortcut to UTokyo. -Shortcut! Yay!
-也就是說，這是上東大的捷徑 -捷徑！太棒啦！
Natural Sciences 2 is easier so you want me to switch?
理科二類比較容易 所以你想讓我轉志願？
That's for losers! No way!
那是輸家才會做的事，我才不要！
You want to get in, don't you? If you want to fail, be my guest.
你想進東大吧？ 要是你想落榜，你就自便吧
My job is simply to get you into UTokyo.
我的工作只是將你送進東大而已
How you feel is not my problem.
你的感受不關我的事
Next, arts.
接下來，文科
Kosugi, Hayase, Seto.
小杉、早瀨、瀨戶
You'll do Humanities and Social Sciences 3.
你們考文科三類
-Okay. -What's that?
-好 -文科三類是什麼？
What's wrong with 1 or 2?
考一類和二類不行嗎？
Humanities and Social Sciences 1 is full of geniuses.
文科一類全是天才
It's ridiculously hard.
難度非常高
And 2 is packed with logical-thinking, clear-headed people.
二類則充滿了 邏輯清楚、思維清晰的人
You've only been studying for a year. It's impossible.
你們只學了一年，是不可能考上的
In comparison, for Humanities 3,
相比起來，文科三類
if you can get 80% on the Common Test,
要是在共通考試拿到80%
you'll pass with 60% on the secondary exam.
第二個考試就能以60%通過
This is the only way you can get into UTokyo.
這是你們能考上東大的唯一方法
Alright!
好！
The only way, even for Kosugi?
就算對小杉來說也很難嗎？
Kosugi could get into 2.
小杉能考上文科二類
I want to study literature, so 3 is fine.
我想學文學，所以考文科三類也可以
-Yay! Let's do this! -Yeah!
-太好了！那一起加油吧！ -嗯
That's it.
就是這樣
If you understand the strategy,
如果你們都明白了策略
let's get class started.
現在就開始上課吧
Yes, sir.
是
I have another special instructor.
今天我請來一位特別講師
-Again? -Yes!
-又來？ -好！
Today's special instructor is…
今天的特別講師是…
you guys.
你們
-Huh? -What?
-咦？ -什麼？
Why a video camera?
攝影機是怎麼回事？
You're going to film each other.
你們現在要互相錄影
Film the lessons you teach.
把你們教的課程錄下來
We're not at a level to teach!
我們才不是能教學的程度！
Exactly. What are you thinking?
對啊，老師在想什麼啊？
You've completely filled your brains with basic knowledge.
你們的大腦已經充滿了基本知識
But knowing things doesn't mean you can use them.
但瞭解知識不代表會運用
You've got to use it!
你們得實際運用看看
Listen. To teach, you must understand that information, digest it,
聽好了，在教學前 必須瞭解一段資訊、消化它
organize it, and be able to use it.
整理它、並有能力運用它
Once you can do that, you'll have true understanding.
一旦你們能做到 就算是真正掌握知識了
By recording it, you can observe your thought processes.
透過錄影能觀察自己的思考過程
It will have great results.
效果顯著
That's true.
說得沒錯
But it's all so sudden.
但這也來得太突然了
I'll do it.
我做
Aim higher than E.
目標是擺脫E
It's nearly summer. There's no use complaining.
快到夏天了，埋怨也沒用
Good, Seto. Try it right now.
很好，瀨戶，現在就來試吧
-Yeah. -Here's the theme for your lesson.
-嗯 -這是你們課程的主題
How to use the word "must."
怎麼運用“must”這個詞
This'll be easy.
小菜一碟
Alright! Class is in session.
好！來上課吧
Um… I'll explain how to use "must."
呃…我來解釋 怎麼用“must”這個詞
"Must" is an auxiliary verb,
“Must”是個助動詞
which means "be obliged to."
意思是“有義務”
It has the same meaning as "have to."
它和“have to”意思相同
"Must" is an auxiliary verb,
“Must”是個助動詞
so the verb following it must be in the present tense.
所以緊接著它的詞必須是現在式
The third person singular present "s"… Yes, it doesn't get used.
第三人稱單數現在式的“s”… 對，不會用在這裡
An example sentence is…
比方說，“你現在得學習！”
And suchlike.
之類的用法
This has been my explanation of how to use "must."
以上就是 我對如何使用“must”的講解
-Excuse me. -Yes.
-不好意思 -是
-I'm not satisfied with that. -Huh?
-我聽不懂 -什麼？
How was it, Kosugi?
怎麼樣，小杉？
-There were a few mistakes. -Huh?!
-有幾處錯誤 -咦？
You said after an auxiliary verb the verb must be present tense.
首先，你說助動詞之後的詞 必須是現在式
That should be the base form.
應該是原形才對
And you said "have to" and "must" mean the same thing.
還有你說“have to” 和“must”的意思相同
But "have to" has an objective meaning.
但“have to”的意思裡 有客觀元素
"Must" is used in cases like a subjective command.
“Must”則在主觀命令下使用
That's the difference.
這就是它們之間的差別
Oh yeah, that.
啊，就是那樣
-Very good, Seto. Sit. -Okay.
-很好，瀨戶，坐吧 -嗯
You gave it a good shot. But why did you make mistakes?
你做得很好，但為什麼犯了錯誤呢？
I guess I just slipped up?
我想是我疏忽了？
-Why'd you slip up? -Why?
-你為什麼會疏忽呢？ -為什麼？
Why? I wasn't expecting to have to teach.
為什麼嘛，我沒預料到需要教學
-Inside my head, I just kinda freaked. -Uh-huh.
-其實我心裡有點慌 -嗯
-And then? -And then… that happens to anyone.
-然後呢？ -然後呢…就像其他人一樣
I get it in my head, but I make mistakes when I say it out loud.
我腦子明白了 但說出來的時候就出錯了
And then?
然後呢？
And then…
然後…
I mean, whatever, right? I won't make mistakes next time.
好了啦！我下次不會再犯錯了
-No. And then? -I'm saying I'll be more careful.
-不行，然後呢？ -我說了，我會更小心
What's the point of making excuses like this?
像這樣一直找藉口有什麼用？
Excuses are key. If you make mistakes and don't make excuses, you won't grow.
藉口就是關鍵，如果不為 自己的錯誤找藉口，你就不會成長
-What do you mean? -There are two kinds of excuses.
-什麼意思？ -有兩種藉口
The excuses of winners and those of losers.
贏家的藉口和輸家的藉口
Losers don't think much.
輸家不會思考太多
They call it an oversight and forget about it.
他們把它稱為疏忽，然後就忘了它
They blame others and try not to take responsibility.
他們責怪別人，不去承擔責任
Meanwhile, when winners make mistakes, they analyze the situation deeply.
同時贏家也會有失誤 他們會深入地分析狀況
They think hard about how to improve and use that next time.
他們會用心地想進步的方法 並在下次用上
Right? Iwasaki.
對嗎，岩崎？
I think you're right.
我想你說得對
LAST DAY OF THE FIRST SEMESTER
（第一學期，最後一天）
Summer break begins tomorrow.
明天就放暑假了
Your summer will dictate how you do on the exam.
這個夏天怎麼過 決定了你們考試的表現
A year from now, whether you're enjoying your summer as a UTokyo student
一年後，你們是否 作為東大生享受夏天
depends on right now.
就看現在了
Spend each day wisely.
明智地度過每一天
Yes, sir.
是
Alright! I'm getting pumped!
好，我已經準備好了！
What's the summer special training?
夏日要進行什麼特訓呢？
Bring on the training!
特訓班，放馬過來吧！
Special training? Don't be spoiled.
特訓班？少來了
Huh?
什麼？
-This summer, you'll study on your own. -Huh?
-這個夏天，你們自己念書 -什麼？
Hang on. You said this summer is important!
等等，你剛剛才說這個夏天很重要！
You're abandoning us?
你要拋棄我們嗎？
I can't do it. I'd be too lonely.
我做不了，太孤單了
What about practice exams?
那模擬考怎麼辦？
Are you all babies?
你們是嬰兒嗎？
The coddling ends here.
我們的呵護就到此為止了
It's time to stand on your own feet.
你們是時候靠自己站起來了
Overcoming this will make you confident.
越過這道坎，會讓你們變得有自信
It'll give you the strength to overcome hardship.
它會給你們撐過困難的力量
This summer, you'll find your true strength.
這個夏天 你們會找到自己真正的力量
True strength…
真正的力量…
But I'm scared.
但我會害怕
So today, just for you,
所以今天，為了你們
Mizuno will teach you a strategy for summer break.
水野會教教你們夏天的策略
Mizuno.
水野
Okay, we're going to do a personality analysis.
好，我們現在來做性格測驗
Personality analysis?
性格測驗？
Say you're going to read some books. You've got your eye on several.
假如說你們打算讀幾本書 你們已經有了書單
So do you read them at the same time?
你們會同時讀好幾本
Or do you finish reading one before you start the next?
還是會讀完一本後，再開始下一本？
Which one are you?
你們屬於哪一個？
I'd read them at the same time. I get bored easily.
我會同時讀，我很容易覺得無聊
I only read illustrated reference books.
我只看圖鑑耶
But I'd read comics at the same time.
但看漫畫的時候，我會同時讀好幾本
-I'd read a bunch at once. -Me too!
-我也會同時讀好多 -我也是！
Not me. I have to read one to the end or I feel weird.
我不會，我需要先完成一本 不然會覺得怪怪的
-I read books from start to finish. -I guess I skim to the end.
-我也是會從頭到尾讀一本書 -我想我也會快速讀到最後
I skip the boring parts though.
但我會跳過無聊的部分
-Okay, I've got it. -Huh? What?
-好，我明白了 -咦？什麼？
Do we pass or fail based on what we choose?
難道我們的選項 代表了我們會通過還是落榜？
Hayase, Seto, Iwasaki, and Kenta are diffusive types.
早瀨、瀨戶、岩崎和健太是擴散型
Diffusive type?
擴散型？
Amano, Kosugi, and Fujii are preservation types.
然後天野、小杉和藤井則是保守型
Preservation type?
保守型？
Hey, we're not in the same group as Kosugi. This is bad.
我們和小杉不在同一組，這可不妙
I want to be preservation type!
我想當保守型！
Oh, come on.
喂
If that's all it took, no one would suffer.
要是這樣就能看出能否通過 就不用那麼辛苦了
What worries me is how much this is freaking you out.
居然這樣就慌張了，真讓人不安
Huh? Who said I was freaking out?
什麼？誰說我慌張了？
How are those two different?
那兩個類型有什麼不同？
Diffusion types take action quickly whenever they find something interesting.
擴散型一旦發現有趣的事情 就會很快行動
The keyword for this type is "excitement."
這個類型的關鍵字是“興奮”
Excitement!
興奮！
The place you study is up to how you feel.
念書的地點取決於你的感受
Study materials should be one book that excites you.
你應該選擇 會讓你覺得興奮的學習資料
Try challenging high-level questions.
試試看挑戰高難度的問題
That sounds like fun.
聽起來很有趣
The preservation type wants to do well and doesn't want to make mistakes.
保守型則是希望好好表現 不犯錯誤的類型
The keywords for this type are, "accumulate confidence and security."
這個類型的關鍵字 是“積累自信和安全感”
Accumulate confidence and security…
積累自信和安全感…
The place to study should always be the same. Where you're comfortable.
你應該在固定的地點念書 一個讓你剛到舒適的地方
Study materials should be focused on completing basic-level exercise books.
學習資料應該以基礎練習題為主
Don't touch the high-level questions.
不要去碰高難度的題目
-Okay. -This is the study method for each type.
-好 -這就是不同類型的學習方法
This summer, completely firm up your base.
這個夏天，把你的基礎鞏固起來吧
People who firm up their bases now will make leaps in the fall.
現在打好基礎的人 到了秋天就會飛起來
You'll see yourself speeding towards UTokyo.
你會發現自己正在快速向東大前進
Also, you've already
還有，你們已經
spoken to your families about the UTokyo entrance exam, right?
和家人說了東大入學考的事，對吧？
From now on, you'll need your family's support.
接下來，你們會需要家人的支援
Make sure they follow the Ten Family Rules.
請他們務必遵守十大家庭條規
Remind your family before summer break begins.
暑假開始前 記得再次提醒你們的家人
Yes, ma'am.
是
I'll be lonely if we can't meet during the break.
暑假無法見面的話，我會很孤單的
We've been together every day.
我們到現在為止每天都待在一起
I wish we could get together somewhere to study.
真希望我們能在某個地方一起念書
Oh!
對了
I know a good place.
我知道一個好地方
Wow, this is great! So big.
哇，太好了！真大
Can we study here?
我們能在這裡念書嗎？
Sure. I'll tell the owner. Keep it up, you guys.
當然了，我會和老闆說，加油啊
-Yeah! Thanks! -Thank you!
-太好了，謝啦 -謝謝
I don't get it! Hey, Amano, do you get this?
我不明白，天野，這個你會嗎？
Oh yeah, that's hard. Hang on a sec.
啊，那有點難，等一等
They're here!
他們來了！
Oh, it's you guys!
什麼嘛，是你們！
Akira!
輝！
What are you guys doing?
你們在幹嘛？
Why are you two here?
你們兩個怎麼在這？
What do you mean? This is our territory.
什麼啊？這可是我們的地盤
-Everyone's here! -Kenta, Kosugi. Welcome!
-大家都到了 -健太，小杉，歡迎
-Let's study together. -Yeah.
-一起學習吧 -好
Great timing, Kosugi.
來得正好，小杉
-I wanted you to help me with this. -Which part?
-我想和你請教這個 -哪個部分？
DAY 2
（第二天）
-We're here! -What gives?!
-我們來啦 -什麼啦
I'm busy. Why did you call me here?
我好忙，你怎麼叫我來這裡？
Fujii! Show me your notes!
藤井，借我看看你的筆記
Huh? Why?
啊？為什麼？
Wow, they're really amazing.
真的耶，真厲害
So easy to understand!
真是簡單明瞭
-They're so different from mine. -Yikes.
-和我的很不同 -慘了
Of course they are. You can copy them if you want.
當然了，你要的話可以讓你列印
Can I? A good student's notes are a great way to study.
可以嗎？看好學生的筆記 也是學習的好方法
-Wow, Fujii baby. -Giving me chills.
-哇，小藤井 -我都雞皮疙瘩了
DAY 3
（第三天）
Kaede's late again.
今天楓又晚回來了
It's summer break. What's she up to?
現在放暑假，她在忙什麼？
She said she'd be training in the school gym.
她說她會在學校的體育館訓練
I'm sure she wants to support the team before the nationals.
她應該是想在全國大賽前 幫羽球隊加油吧
How can she be so thoughtful towards others?
她怎麼這麼會為其他人著想？
I know, right?
對啊
I wish she'd think about herself more than about others.
與其擔心別人，還不如先擔心自己
DAY 7
（第七天）
Good work everyone!
大家辛苦了！
Everyone's working hard, so I brought ice cream!
大家那麼努力，我帶了冰淇淋給大家
-Thank you very much! -Okay!
-謝謝 -好
-Yeah! -Let's open it!
-耶！ -快打開吧
-Yummy! -Yum! Sweet!
-美味！ -好吃！真甜！
You two are really part of the gang.
小橋跟岩井根本完全融入我們了
-Getting in on the ice cream. -Seriously!
-還趁機一起吃冰 -真的！
You did a horrible thing to Ms. Mizuno and Mr. Sakuragi.
你們對水野老師 和櫻木老師做了很糟糕的事
That was for Kaede's sake!
那是為了楓！
What? For me?
什麼？為了我？
Yeah!
對啊
We heard you were in trouble from Akira, right?
那時我們聽輝說妳有麻煩，對吧？
So we said we'd help out.
所以我們就說我們會幫忙
-What? That's so nice! -Right?
-什麼啊？你們人很好嘛 -是吧？
In the end, I peed my pants though.
不過最後，我尿褲子了
Hey, laugh!
喂，笑嘛！
Why doesn't anyone laugh?
怎麼沒人笑？
You too, laugh!
你也是，給我笑！
-Hello? -Kaede. Where are you?
-喂？ -楓，妳在哪？
Uh, now?
呃，現在？
I need you to come here right away.
妳現在立刻過來我這裡
Now?
現在？
Right away.
馬上過來
Kaede!
楓！
-Mom! What's going on? -Don't worry about it, just come.
-媽，怎麼突然叫我來？ -別擔心，跟我過來就是了
It's Coach Sugai from the Nihon Unisys corporate team.
是日本優利職業隊的菅井教練
There's no practice today, so he agreed to meet with us!
今天沒有練習，他就答應見我們了
-Nihon Unisys? -Look!
-日本優利職業隊？ -看！
Your dad pulled a lot of strings for you!
妳爸為了妳花了不少人脈！
We have athletes who are off the front line due to injury.
我們也有因傷而從前線退下的運動員
They keep training in ways that don't harm their knees.
他們繼續以不傷害膝蓋的方式訓練
Will you train with us?
妳能和我們一起訓練嗎？
It's not normally allowed, but there's special summer training.
一般是不被允許的，但有個夏日特訓
If it's okay with you, you can join us.
要是妳願意，妳可以加入我們
You're an Olympic hopeful.
妳可是未來的奧運人選
Our athletes would welcome you.
我們的運動員會很歡迎妳的
Isn't that great?
這不是太好了嗎？
Is that really alright?
真的沒問題嗎？
Yes. But it's very rigorous.
是，但這非常嚴苛
It's a month of solid practice.
那是為期一個月的扎實訓練
-A month? -You can see top athletes close up.
-一個月？ -妳可以和頂尖的運動員近距離接觸
It's an amazing chance to learn.
是個學習的好機會
Please allow her to join.
請務必讓她加入
Thank you very much.
拜託你了
You too!
妳也要！
NIHON UNISYS CORPORATE TEAM
（日本優利職業隊）
Stop! Iwasaki, don't flinch. Don't look down.
停！岩崎，別退縮，別往下看
-Yes, sir! -Alright.
-是 -好
-What are you guys up to? -Hey, sir!
-你們在幹嘛？ -哦，老師
Can't you see what we're doing?
你看不出來嗎？
We do study a little, don't you know.
我們偶爾也會念書的
Waseda or Keio
早稻田或者慶應
should be a piece of cake.
應該是小菜一碟
Waseda or Keio?
早稻田或慶應？
Huh, what?
咦？怎麼了？
You're in for hell.
你們會見到地獄
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Private schools only test three subjects so it seems easy.
私立大學只考三個科目 所以表面上看起來很簡單
Most faculties at Keio with high hurdles from essay questions.
慶應大多的科系 都會出高難度的論述題
Stuff you'd never see on a UTokyo exam,
那些你在東大入學考不會遇到的東西
like difficult English words.
比如困難的英文單字
Things that barely appear in huge prep books.
那些主要參考書都不會教的東西
There are extremely niche questions.
非常冷門的問題
What?
什麼？
For schools like Waseda and Keio,
換句話說 像早稻田和慶應這樣的學校
there are infinite possibilities for the range of exam questions.
考試的出題範圍等同於無限大
Without major knowledge and adaptability,
缺乏專業知識和靈活度
you'll never break through that barrier.
你們是沒辦法跨過那道坎的
-Change your strategy. -Sheesh.
-改變你們的策略吧 -哎
-Are my guys studying here? -Yeah, every day.
-那些人在這念書嗎？ -嗯，每一天都有來
I don't see Kaede lately though.
但我最近沒見到楓
Pass on a message for me.
幫我轉達一個訊息
Tomorrow's a school day. Don't forget.
明天是返校日，別忘了
-Okay. -Got it.
-好 -收到
Long time no see, sir.
好久不見了，老師
-Whoa. Long time no see, Sakamoto. -Yes.
-哇，好久不見了，坂本 -對啊
It's your fault I'm roped into this lost cause.
都是你害我蹚這趟渾水
You figured out it was me who found you.
你發現了是我找到你的呢
Only you could.
就只有你能做到
Mizuno-senpai asked me to find out who sent that e-mail.
水野前輩請我找出傳那封電郵的人
Relating to the sale of Tatsumi Gakuen.
關於龍海學園出售那件事
Sending it anonymously. That's in bad taste.
發匿名信，真是沒品
Seriously. Even so, buying up all this land?
對啊，不過把這所有的土地買起來
-What are they going to do? -What indeed.
-他們打算做什麼？ -對啊
If you find out, let me know.
要是你查到了，讓我知道
President Sakamoto.
坂本社長
-See ya. -Bye.
-那再見了 -再見
MID-BREAK SCHOOL DAY
（暑假返校日）
After the next practice exam ends,
下個模擬考之後
write down everything from your answer papers.
大家要另外再重寫一份 答題紙上的全部內容
Everything? I can't remember all that.
全部？我記不起來啦
They're essay questions and there are a ton of them.
那都是論述題，而且問題很多耶
You write a draft before answering the question, right?
妳在答題之前會先打草稿，對吧？
Use that to remember.
用那來幫妳回想起來
And bring them here.
然後把它們帶回來這裡
-What for? -To mark yourself.
-要做什麼呢？ -要幫自己打分數
What?
什麼？
It takes weeks for the results to come back.
成績在考試幾週後才會公布
You want to find your mistakes quickly,
你會想要儘快找出你的錯誤
analyze how to improve, and build a strategy.
分析怎麼進步，還有制定一個策略
Overcome your shortfalls quickly.
來快速解決你的弱點
That's what's needed now.
這就是現在需要做的
Huh.
哦
One more thing. There's a great benefit to marking your own test.
還有一件事 給自己批改考卷有個大好處
Amano, do you know why?
天野，你知道為什麼嗎？
You get to know question trends?
你能知道出題的趨勢？
You're half right.
你對了一半
Listen. By marking yourself,
聽著，透過批改自己的試卷
you can see where you get points and lose points.
能看出自己在哪裡獲得分數 在哪裡失去分數
Through repetition, you'll see the intent of the ones making and scoring the exam.
重複幾次後 你就會明白出題人和批改人的意圖
You'll get to know what sort of answers they're looking for.
你就會明白他們要的是怎樣的答案
If it were that easy, we wouldn't suffer.
要是有這麼容易 我們就不用那麼辛苦了
Correct, you'll suffer less.
沒錯，你會吃少一些苦
If you can do this,
要是你能這麼做
you'll figure out what answers UTokyo wants.
你就會搞清楚東大想要的答案是什麼
-Wow. -I see.
-好厲害 -原來如此
But knowing the results right after it's over makes me nervous.
但考完試後就馬上知道成績 會讓我很緊張
Maybe I'll get a higher score.
或許我的等級會提高呢
Yeah, we've been working hard every day. Of course it'll go up.
對啊，我們每天都很努力 當然會提升了
I bet I could get a D.
我這次一定能拿到D
Don't get your hopes up.
別抱太大期望了
Huh?
什麼？
The athletes who finished their summer events will be at these exams.
那些結束了夏天活動的運動員們 會參加這些考試
They have energy, strength, perseverance, and focus.
他們有精力、體力、毅力和專注力
They're strong, they have it all.
他們很強，什麼都具備了
The number of test takers will go up and so will the average score.
考生的數量會提高，平均分也一樣
Even if you score higher, you might not get a higher grade.
即使你拿到了更高分 也可能不會得到更高的等級
Strong opponents will come at you from all sides.
更強的對手會從四面八方向你湧來
Whoa. Scary!
哇，恐怖！
So you approach it with even more energy than ever. Got it?
所以要拿出幹勁來面對，明白了嗎？
Yes, sir.
是
I have to do this.
我一定要做到
AFTER THE SUMMER UTOKYO PRACTICE EXAM
（夏天東大模擬考，結束後）
Good morning!
早安！
-Good morning. -Morning!
-早安 -早！
Okay, I'll collect the answer sheets.
好，我會收集答題卷
Collect? Don't we mark our own?
收集？我們不是批改自己的試卷嗎？
Shuffle them, and mark each other.
我們要把它們打亂，互相批改
What?
什麼？
N-No! I don't want anyone to see.
不…不要！我不想讓其他人看
Yeah, can't we just correct it ourselves and review?
對啊，自己畫圈複習題目就好了吧
-Are any of yours correct? -Hush.
-是圈就好了 -很煩欸
If you mark another person's answers,
批改其他人的答案
it's beneficial.
是有好處的
What kind of benefit?
什麼樣的好處？
People have trouble noticing their own mistakes.
人們很難注意到自己的錯誤
But they instantly notice others' mistakes.
但能馬上看出其他人的錯誤
By marking another person's test,
透過批改另一人的試卷
you'll notice the parts that are easily mistaken.
你會注意到容易出錯的部分
You'll make new discoveries and level up.
你會有新的發現，並升級
-We can level up? -Level up!
-我們能升級？ -升級！
If you get it, then hurry up and give them to me.
如果你明白了，就快點交出來吧
-Okay. -Got it.
-好 -明白
-What? I'm embarrassed! -Come on.
-什麼？真是丟臉！ -來
Everyone has an answer booklet, right?
大家手上都有一份答題冊，對吧？
Read the explanations, note how points are added and taken off.
仔細讀解說，注意怎麼給分和扣分
-Then mark those tests. -Yes, ma'am.
-然後開始改考卷 -是
Ready, start.
準備，開始
Kosugi really is super amazing.
小杉果然很厲害
Whoa, but she made one mistake here.
啊，但她這裡犯了個錯誤
If even Kosugi can miss that, anyone could.
連小杉都會寫錯 代表大家都有可能錯在這裡
Hayase is getting a solid score on the humanities subjects.
早瀨的文科科目都有拿到基本分
Her reading comprehension is much better.
她的閱讀理解進步了好多
Huh. Even Amano is doing well on his English essays.
天野這傢伙英文作文都有寫到重點
I missed that one. Damn.
我少寫了那個，可惡
Kenta did great. All the science subjects have high marks.
不愧是健太 所有理科科目都拿到了高分
Compared to him, I got these wrong.
比起他，我做錯了這些
Fujii. Right, right, wrong, right, right.
藤井，對、對、錯、對、對
Right, right, wrong, right, right…
對、對、錯、對、對…
Kaede missed this one too.
楓的這一題也錯了
This too.
還有這
Announcing the practice exam results.
現在公布模擬考成績
Kenta.
健太
201 points.
201分
-Mari, I did it! -Yeah!
-麻里，我做到啦！ -嗯！
Kosugi.
小杉
-225 points. -Yes ma'am.
-225分 -是
Fujii.
藤井
171 points.
171分
Oh!
哦！
Amano.
天野
129 points.
129分
Yeah!
太好了！
Hayase.
早瀨
138 points.
138分
Yikes! Really?
不是吧！真的？
Seto.
瀨戶
111 points.
111分
Yes! Yes!
太好啦！
Iwasaki.
岩崎
122 points.
122分
Is this really mine? It went up a lot.
這真是我的嗎？進步了好多呢
Yes, yes!
太棒了！
If you improved a lot or not,
不管你們是不是進步了許多
these results aren't everything.
這些成績並不代表全部
Yes. You started with basic junior high school knowledge.
沒錯，你們從國中基礎知識學起
You've got the base, now if you can add to that,
你們已經有了基礎 現在如果能更進一步
you'll leap forward.
你們就能向前飛躍
Don't panic. Just do what you can as hard as you can. That's all.
別慌張，盡你所能全力以赴，就這樣
Yes, sir.
是
Hey, are you feeling sick?
妳的狀態不好嗎？
Your score barely changed from last time.
妳的分數和上次差不多
Hayase and Amano passed you.
早瀨和天野都超越了妳
It's just summer fatigue. I'm fine.
只是夏季疲勞而已，我沒事
Are you really okay, Kaede?
妳真的沒事，楓？
I said I'm fine!
我說了我沒事！
Iwasaki.
岩崎
Come with me.
跟我來
I'm really just a little tired lately.
我最近只是有點累
I'll recover.
我會恢復的
Iwasaki.
岩崎
Do you remember what I told you before?
妳還記得我之前跟妳說的話嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
You've decided your life up to now.
妳目前為止的人生全都是妳的決定
And you will from here on, too.
現在開始接下來的人生也一樣
Make a choice you can stand behind.
妳要做出負責任的決定
Iwasaki-senpai, hello!
岩崎前輩，妳好！
-Hello! -Iwasaki, why…
-妳好！ -岩崎，為什麼…
-Long time no see, everyone. -Long time no see!
-好久不見了，各位 -好久不見！
Hey! Get back to practice!
喂！回去訓練！
Yes, sir! Pardon me.
是！不好意思
Looks like the nationals are going well.
看來全國大賽進行得很順利呢
Of course.
當然
Anyway, I heard from my parents.
話說，我聽我父母說了
You're practicing with Nihon Unisys?
妳在日本優利訓練？
Weren't you going to UTokyo?
妳不是要上東大嗎？
Do you think you can win without committing to either?
妳這種搖擺不定的狀況 要怎麼達到目標？
-It's none of your business. -Yeah, it's not.
-這不關妳的事 -這是不關我的事
But I just think it's uncool behavior for a former ace.
但我覺得之前的王牌這麼做很遜
I know I'm only doing a half-hearted job.
我也知道自己很半調子
But I've got a lot going on.
但我要煩的事情很多
A lot?
很多？
I disappointed my parents with my injury.
我受傷的事讓父母很失望
If I tell them I'm going to UTokyo instead of practicing,
如果我告訴他們我不訓練了 我現在要上東大
I'll disappoint them again.
我會再次讓他們失望
Don't disappoint me!
妳才別讓我失望！
You're not like that, are you?
妳不是這樣的人，對吧？
Are you in a position to worry about that?
妳現在是擔心那些的時候嗎？
28…
28…
Lift it! Lift it!
舉起來！
Go! 29!
繼續！29！
Lift your racket!
舉起妳的球拍！
Hey!
喂！
Sorry.
對不起
Kaede, focus! Focus!
楓，專注啊專注！
-Yes, sir. -Hold it well. Your racket is your life!
-是 -給我好好抓住！球拍就是妳的命！
Yes, sir.
是
You followed her all the way there instead of studying?
妳不去念書，還跑去跟蹤她？
I'm worried!
因為我很擔心啊
It was Kaede who inspired me to try for UTokyo.
是楓讓我想要嘗試考東大的
I can't just ignore this.
我不能視而不見
Nihon Unisys. A top-ranking badminton team.
日本優利，是一流的羽球隊
Kaede's parents are really strict.
楓的父母很嚴格
I saw them at her match before. They've given their lives to badminton.
之前比賽我見過他們 有種羽球就是生命的感覺
I think Kaede's scared to tell them she's taking the UTokyo entrance exam.
我想楓應該不敢告訴他們 她要考東大入學考
Sir, do something for her.
老師，幫幫她吧
Yeah. Talk to Kaede's parents.
對啊，和她父母談談吧
I just know Kaede wants to focus on studying.
楓一定也想專心念書考東大
Say something!
說點什麼啊！
You convinced Amano and my parents.
你說服了天野和我的父母
And Kosugi too. Why are you ignoring Kaede?
小杉那時也是 為什麼對楓你卻袖手旁觀？
Everything depends on this summer.
是你自己說的，這個暑假很關鍵
It's Iwasaki's problem. You guys shouldn't get involved.
這是岩崎的問題，你們不應該插手
-Yeah, but… -Everything depends on this summer.
-但是… -對一年後的你們而言
Where will you be a year from now?
這個暑假也很關鍵
Long time no see!
好久不見
Kaede! Hey, are you feeling okay?
楓！妳沒事吧？
Yeah. I'm fine.
嗯，我很好
You didn't have Nihon Unisys practice today?
今天日本優利沒有訓練嗎？
How do you know that?
你怎麼知道的？
Sorry, I followed you and saw you practicing.
對不起，我跟著妳，看到妳訓練了
Why didn't you tell us? We're friends, right?
妳為什麼不告訴我們？ 我們不是朋友嗎？
-We'll convince your parents. -Stop.
-我們會說服妳父母的 -不要
I can do both.
我可以兼顧
Kaede…
楓…
You can't do both, idiot. Are you mocking UTokyo?
妳兼顧不了的，笨蛋 妳在小看東大嗎？
Hey Kaede, at this rate you're really in trouble.
楓，妳這樣下去真的不妙
Summer is crunch time. The teacher said.
這個暑假很關鍵，老師說的
I know!
我知道！
I know that the most.
我最清楚了
That I'm being half-hearted.
我現在不過是半調子
I know that.
我知道的
Can't we help somehow? We're friends.
我們能幫妳什麼嗎？我們是朋友
I'll do whatever I can to help.
我也會盡力幫妳
You helped me before.
妳之前幫過我
We can all think of a way together.
我們可以一起想想辦法
That's a good idea.
那是個好主意
But you know you've got to work this out fast and focus on studying.
但妳得快點想出辦法，然後專心學習
Iwasaki, let's think together.
岩崎，我們一起想吧
Sorry, but…
對不起，但…
this is my problem.
這是我的問題
Kaede?
楓？
-Kaede? -Kaede!
-楓？ -楓！
Are you okay? Kaede!
妳還好嗎？楓！
I…
我…
Lack of sleep and fatigue was the cause. You're working too hard.
暈倒的原因是睡眠不足和疲累 妳把自己逼得太緊了
I'm sorry.
對不起
Your parents are coming to get you. Rest here until then.
妳父母會來接妳，先在這裡休息吧
Huh?
什麼？
Hey!
喂！
-Iwasaki! -Kaede!
-岩崎！ -楓！
Settle down, Iwasaki. Just talk, your parents will--
冷靜點，岩崎 只要好好解釋，妳父母一定會…
Kaede.
楓
Kaede!
楓！
Stop! Kaede, stop!
停！楓，別跑了！
Let go! I'm really fine!
放手！我真的沒事！
People who insist they're fine usually aren't.
那些一直說自己沒事的人通常都有事
You'll never get into UTokyo as you are now. Give up.
現在的妳 是不可能考進東大的，放棄吧
You're kicked out.
妳被踢出專科了
Why? That's horrible!
為什麼？這太過分了！
I already said this. People who aren't expected to pass are kicked out.
我已經說過了 沒有希望錄取的人會被踢出去
Give up on Iwasaki.
所以得放棄岩崎
What are you saying?
你說什麼？
You'd abandon a student?
你要放棄學生嗎？
People who can't face themselves are doomed to be losers.
不能面對自己的人註定要當輸家
She's running from her weakness.
她在逃避自己的弱點
Trying to avert her eyes.
試著轉移注意力
That sort of person could never get into UTokyo.
那種人是無法進東大的
But sir…
等等，老師…
Wait.
等等
I want to go to UTokyo.
我想上東大
I really want to go!
我真的想上！
Why can't you say that to your parents?
為什麼妳不能告訴父母？
I just…
那…
I'm at fault.
是我的錯
I'm asking why you can't say that to your parents.
我在問妳，為什麼不能告訴父母
Because…
因為…
I could never say that.
我哪說得出口？
Why could you never say it?
為什麼妳說不出口？
They'd never accept it.
他們不會接受的
Why?
為什麼？
They'd make me quit the course.
他們會讓我退出專科
It's all because
這全都是因為
I don't have courage.
我沒有勇氣
Why don't you have courage?
妳為什麼沒有勇氣？
I'm scared.
我害怕
I'm scared of disappointing them again.
我害怕再讓他們失望
I disappointed them when I got injured. I can't do it again.
我受傷已經讓他們失望過 我不能再這麼做了
It scares me.
我很害怕
My parents are supporting my dream.
我父母很支持我的夢想
They're working so hard to make it happen.
他們拼了命地想讓它成真
You're a kind person.
妳是一個體貼的人
But you're not a truly kind person.
但這不是真正的體貼
You don't tell your parents that they're hurting you.
妳不告訴父母，他們正在傷害妳
Is that kindness?
這怎麼算體貼？
Iwasaki, they may be family,
岩崎，他們是妳的家人
but you don't have to take on your parents' expectations.
但妳不需要承擔他們的期望
Your parents have their lives. And you have your life.
妳父母有自己的人生 妳也有妳自己的人生
You have to take on your own life.
妳必須承擔妳自己的人生
Listen.
聽好了
Parents are monsters.
父母是怪獸
They care for you longer and stronger than anyone.
他們比任何人都更長時間地 更強烈地在意妳
If you want to make them understand,
如果妳想讓他們理解
you have to be ready to cut ties.
妳就必須有斷絕關係的決心
That conviction is necessary, isn't it?
這種覺悟是必須的，不是嗎？
Kaede!
楓！
Are you alright?
妳沒事吧！
I'm okay. Sorry I made you worry.
我沒事，讓你們擔心了，對不起
Idiot! I told you to take care of your health.
笨蛋！我跟妳說過要注意健康管理
I'm always saying that, aren't I?
我常常叮嚀妳的，不是嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Anyway, I'm glad it's not serious.
無論如何，沒大礙真是萬幸
You can go back tomorrow, can't you?
妳明天就能回去訓練了，對吧？
About that…
那個…
What is it?
怎麼了？
I…
我…
I'm not going to Nihon Unisys practice anymore.
我不會再去日本優利的訓練了
What do you mean? Did something happen?
什麼意思？發生了什麼事嗎？
-No. -Then why?
-不是 -那為什麼？
I pulled so many strings to get you into that practice.
我拜託了那麼多人才把妳送進去
I'm taking the UTokyo exam.
我要考東大
UTokyo? That UTokyo?
東大？那個東大？
-You're joking… -I'm not joking.
-妳在開玩笑… -我沒在開玩笑
What about the Olympics? You've given up?
奧運怎麼辦？妳放棄了？
A little injury like that and you give up?
就因為那點小傷，妳就放棄了？
Something we've built up over more than ten years?
我們辛苦耕耘了十年以上的努力？
You'd throw it away?
妳這麼簡單就捨棄掉了？
I never said I was giving up. Listen to the end…
我沒說我要放棄，聽我說完…
Dear!
老公！
I'm serious about this.
我是認真的
About UTokyo and the Olympics too.
對東大，對奧運也是
I'll do both. I swear I'll do both.
我兩邊都可以做到 我發誓我兩邊都可以做到
That's ridiculous. You could never do that.
荒謬，妳是做不到的
I can. If I never give up, I'll find a way.
我能，如果不放棄，我就會找到方法
I learned that in the UTokyo course.
這是我在東大專科學到的
Don't be ridiculous!
別胡說八道了！
I never said you could join that course.
我從來沒允許過妳參加東大專科
How selfish of you!
妳怎麼能那麼自私！
I'm willing to cut ties to make this happen!
我是抱持著和你們 斷絕關係的決心告訴你們的！
You said something before.
爸，你之前說過這樣的話
Studying is for people with no talent. Something common people do.
學習是給沒才能的普通人做的事
But you were wrong.
但你錯了
I learned a lot at the UTokyo course.
我在東大專科學了很多
Not just knowledge. Things I'll need in life.
不只是知識，還有我人生中需要的事
I've learned a lot.
我學了很多
Plus,
而且
I've made valuable friends.
我還交了重要的朋友
So I can say for sure that studying isn't a waste of time.
所以我能很肯定地說 學習並沒有浪費時間
I want to study sports medicine at UTokyo.
我想要在東大學運動醫學
And keep studying after I go to the Olympics.
奧運之後也想繼續
For a long time.
繼續…
I always want to be involved with badminton.
我想繼續做跟羽毛球有關的事
I want to study so I can help athletes who are struggling with injuries.
我想學習，才能幫助那些 因為受傷而掙扎的運動員
I want to study at UTokyo!
我要在東大學習！
That's why
所以
I'm asking you.
拜託你們
Dad, Mom.
爸爸，媽媽
Please support me.
請支持我
Please.
拜託了
SECOND SEMESTER
（第二學期）
Here we go!
來了！
Say cheese!
來，笑一個！
So gloomy! Be a little more…
真是憂鬱，再多一點…
-Smile! -Best four!
-笑！ -前四強！
Hooray!
太好了！
That's great.
好了！
Iwasaki.
岩崎
Hello.
妳好
Thanks for the other day.
那天謝謝妳
Thanks to you, I faced my weakness.
多虧妳，我面對了自己的軟弱
Best four at the nationals.
全國大賽前四強
Congratulations.
恭喜妳
See ya.
再見了
You'd better get in!
妳最好考上！
When we're playing doubles at the Olympics,
我們在奧運一起打雙打的時候
you've gotta be a UTokyo student
妳最好有東大學生的頭銜
or we won't be a good pair.
不然可配不上我這搭檔
Same goes for you. Live up to my title.
妳也一樣，別辜負我的頭銜
Show Seinan what you've got.
讓青南大學看看妳的實力
Of course I will.
當然了
DAYS UNTIL THE COMMON TEST
（共通考試前137天）
We're less than halfway to the first Common Test in January.
距離一月的第一次共通考試 我們已經超過半路了
The countdown to the entrance exam starts now.
入學考的倒數現在開始
Listen.
聽好了
Laugh or cry, there are 137 days left.
笑也好哭也好，我們只剩下137天
And you might as well laugh.
既然如此，最後就笑著面對吧！
Yes, sir!
是！
What's up guys? Aren't you going to study?
你們怎麼了？不念書嗎？
But we'll never get in.
但我們不可能考上了
You said it, we could never do it.
老師你說過的，我們不可能做到
I did say Waseda or Keio were impossible.
我說早稻田和慶應不可能
But I don't remember saying UTokyo was impossible.
但我沒說東大不可能
Huh?
什麼？
With UTokyo, it all depends on how you approach it.
東大的話，就看你們的方法了
We have the space. Why not observe from the back?
我們這裡還有空間 要不先在後面觀察一下？
But there's not enough time.
但時間不夠了
Why not join as trainees?
要不來當練習生？
Only thing, you have to bring your own desk and chair.
不過，你們得自己帶桌椅過來
Yes, sir!
是
Did you figure it out? Who sent that e-mail?
你查出來了嗎？那封電郵是誰寄的？
No, I couldn't. They went through a foreign server.
不，查不到，他們用了外國的伺服器
I couldn't figure it out.
完全查不出來
Okay, got it. Thanks.
這樣啊，我明白了，謝謝
It's a nice place. Tatsumi Gakuen.
真是個好地方啊，龍海學園
Yes. It's finally time.
是啊，終於啊
I can hardly wait.
實在是太迫不及待了呢
UTOKYO EXAM &amp; BUYOUT DRAMA!
（東大考試和收購劇 W大逆轉前篇！）
A year ago, could any of you have imagined this day?
你們有誰在去年的現在 曾想像過今天的景象？
I want to try.
我想嘗試
I'll stake my life.
我會拿我的人生做賭注
Five Rules to Prep for the Common Test.
共通考試的心態五大守則
-Magic? -That's right!
-魔法？ -對！
-That does make sense. -Do not fear it.
-的確很好懂 -不足為懼
You'll take it as if it's the real thing.
你們要用正式上場的心態去考
Yes, sir!
是
You might feel bad now, but working towards your UTokyo goal is happiness.
也許現在會覺得很痛苦 但可以向東大努力可是很幸福的
-You're trying to get into UTokyo? -Poor thing!
-你想上東大嗎？ -好可憐喔
Trust the students, right?
要相信學生，對吧？
They can fight alone.
他們已經能獨立迎戰了
It's alright. They'll get the points to pass.
沒問題，他們會考到及格分的
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻譯：楊易